어지러운 전국 시대.
It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
카라쿠리인이 사는 지팡구국에서는 군웅할거하여 밤낮으로 접전이 계속되고
Jipang Country, where the Karakuri people live, is a place of constant conflict.
카라쿠리 무예가들도 승리와 영광을 꿈꾸며 맹렬히 싸우고 있었다.
Karakuri Martial Artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
그리고 지금, 카라쿠리 무예자 제일을 꿈꾸는 터무니없는 영웅이 탄생했다!
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri Martial Artist!
무사시 등장이오!
Musashi enters-dasu!
카라쿠리 검호전: 무사시 로드
Karakuri Kengouden
Musashi Road
(The Story of Karakuri Martial Artist: Road of Musashi)
사내는 언제나 세계 한가운데서
A man always dreams of the day
제일 강해질 날을
when he'll become the world's
아! 아! 꿈꿔라
AH! AH! strongest
마음의 칼을 넓은 하늘로 번쩍 쳐들어
Raise your spirit's sword high to the wide sky
모험의 길의 막을 연다
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
지팡구국을 떠도는 검호
A skilled Martial Artist wanders Jipang Country
그 이름은 카라쿠리인 무사시
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
격렬한 칼의 소리가
An intense clash of swords
눈부신 인생
makes life dazzling
싸웠던 어제보다도 오늘 강해진다
Yesterday's battles makes you stronger today
무예! 이도류 무사시
Martial Art! Dual Blade Musashi
내일은 빛난다
Tomorrow will be glorious
격렬한 칼의 소리가
An intense clash of swords
눈부신 인생
makes life dazzling
싸우는 한껏 고요함과 함께
Fight your hardest with tranquility
무예! 이도류 무사시
Martial Art! Dual Blade Musashi
미간이 빛나고 있었다 무사시!!
Shining brow! Musashi!
노부나가의 메가톤성은 에도토피아를 불바다로 만든다.
Nobunaga's Megaton Castle made Edotopia into a fire of sea.
어떻게든 저지한 무사시 일행이었지만, 고전을 강요당했다.
Musashi and others stopped them somehow, but they were forced into a hard fight.
그러나 거기에 나타난 것은 국왕 전하의 초공전.
But, what appeared there was the king's Chokuden.
무사시 일행은 메가톤성에 쳐들어가, 도쿠간류를 쓰러트렸다.
Musashi and others got into Megaton Castle, and took down Dokuganryu.
꽃의 무사시
악을 베오
Flowering Musashi
Cuts the Evil
에잇, 이대로는 에도토피아가!
Damn, what will happen to Edotopia now?!
오, 센히메!
Senhime!
할아버지!
Grandpa!
이런 곳에서 뭘 하고 있냐. 어서 달아나야지!
What are you doing here? We have to escape!
아니.
Nope.
저 겐나이 씨라는 대단한 발명가가 한방에 에도토피아의 불을 꺼 주겠대!
That great inventor named Mr. Gennai is going to put off the fire on whole Edotopia at once!
한방에?
At once?
어!
Yeah!
어이, 망치 돌려 줘!
Hey, give me back the hammer!
마지막 마무리다!
It's for finishing!
네!
Yeah!
좋아!
Right!
국왕 전하.
Your Highness.
이에야스여, 이렇게 되었으니 어쩔 수 없다.
Ieyasu, this leaves me no choice.
나는 결심했다.
I made a decision.
국왕 전하.
Your Highness.
국왕 전하는 노부나가에게 삼종의 신기의 하나인 성검을 넘길 생각이십니다.
The Highness is going to hand over the remaining one of the Three Sacred Treasure, the sacred sword, to Nobunaga.
성검을? 어째서.
The sacred sword? Why?
에도토피아에게 사는 자들을 구하기 위해서라면 성검은 아깝지 않아.
Saving everyone of Edotopia worths more than the sacred sword.
그러면 국왕의 자리를 노부나가에 넘겨주는 것이 됩니다.
That means you're handing over the seat of the king to Nobunaga.
그것도 괜찮지 않겠어?
That's not necessarily a bad idea.
노부나가도, 남의 자식. 설마 지팡구의 사람들을 몰살시키지는 않을 게야.
Nobunaga is also somebody's child. He won't massacre everyone in Jipangu.
분명 새로운 나라를 만들어 주겠지.
He'll make a new country for everyone.
국왕 전하는 어찌 되는 건가요?
What will happen to you, your Highness?
나는 닛코에서 하이쿠라도 만들면서 여생을 보냅니다.
I'll spend the rest of my life at Nikko, writing Haikus.
국왕 전하, 가여워...
Your Highness, what a pity...
그래, 하나 생각났어.
Yes, I just made one.
노부나가가
성검을 가져가도
용서를 해 줘.
Do forgive me
even if Nobunaga
gets the sacred sword.
그럼.
Well then.
흥. 건방진 무사시 놈들을 쓰러트릴 동안 에도토피아는 예쁘게 타고 있구나.
Hmph. While we're taking down those impudent Musashi and others, Edotopia is burning up pretty.
기분 좋구나.
This is great.
자, 무사시는 이 내가 직접 단칼에 베어 주겠다.
I will cut off Musashi with one slash by myself.
한조! 안내해라!
Hanzo! Guide me.
예! 노부나가 님!
Yessir, Mr. Nobunaga!
또 왔구나! 쳐부숴라!
They're here again! Destroy it!
노부나가 님. 백기입니다.
Mr. Nobunaga. They're with a white flag.
저건 삼종의 신기 중 하나, 성검.
That is one of the Three Sacred Treasures, the sacred sword.
놈들, 드디어 항복했구나.
They finally surrendered.
좋아, 다가가라.
Get closer.
노부나가 님. 무사시 놈들은 어쩝니까.
Mr. Nobunaga. What should we do with Musashi and others?
못 달아나게 가두어 두어라!
Lock them in, so that they won't get away!
예!
Yessir!
야! 노부나가! 어디 있소! 어서 나오시오! 야!
Hey! Nobunaga! Where are you-dasu?! Come out immediately-dasu! Hey!
달려라!
Run!
저런! 갇혔구나!
No! We're trapped!
젠장! 이런 벽 따위 내가 부숴 보이겠소!
Damn! I'll destroy these walls-dasu!
-괜찮냐?
-괜찮습니까?
Are you alright?
틀렸소.
It didn't work-dasu.
성검은 잘 받았다!
I now got the sacred sword!
이걸로 에도토피아 공격은 그만해 주십시오.
Please stop attacking Edotopia now.
그러니까, 다른 공격을 하면 곤란합니다. 즉, 이 세상에 평화를. 온건히, 온건히, 둥글게, 둥글게.
I believe that you won't do further attack. In other words, bring peace to this world. Moderately and harmoniously.
알고 있다. 나라고 해도 공격하는 건 본의가 아니었다.
I know. Attacking was not my original intention.
부탁합니다.
Please.
곡옥에 방패에 성검. 국왕의 증표인 삼종의 신기가 모였구나.
The jewel, the shield, and the sacred sword. The certificate of the king, the Three Sacred Treasure, are now here.
이걸로 지팡구국은 내 것이다!
With these, Jipangu Country is mine!
한조! 너도 기뻐해라!
Hanzo! You should be happy, too!
정말로 축하드립니다.
Congratulations with all my respect.
지팡구국은 내 것이다!
Jipangu Country is mine!
하, 한조...
H- Hanzo...
노부나가. 삼종의 신기는 내가 가져가겠다!
Nobunaga! I shall claim the Three Sacred Treasures!
배신했나, 한조. 네 목숨을 구한 건 이 나다!
Did you betray me, Hanzo? I'm the one who saved your life!
흥.
Hmph.
조조의 갑옷을 준 이 나를 배신하다니...
How dare you betray me, who gave you Sousou Armor?
죽어라, 노부나가!
Die, Nobunaga!
네놈도 함께 지옥에 떨어져라!
I'll take you to the hell with me!
거의 다 된 일을...
I was so close...
삼종의 신기에 메가톤성. 이걸로 지팡구국은 내 것이다!
The Three Sacred Treasures and Megaton Castle. Jipangu Country is now mine!
좋아, 됐다.
It's now done.
겐나이 씨, 어서, 어서!
Mr. Gennai, hurry, hurry!
한번에 에도토피아의 불을 끈다는 것은, 이 기계에서 대량의 물이라도 나오는 걸까?
If it can put off all the fire on Edotopia, then would it produce a large amount of water?
대체 뭐가 일어나고 있는 거야?
What's going on inside that?
폭풍을 부른다.
It's calling for a storm.
포, 폭풍?
S- storm?
그리하면 이 정도의 불은 한 순간에 사라지겠지.
By doing that, a fire like this will be put off at once.
그래도...
But...
그렇게 간단히 폭풍이 올지...
I don't think you can call a storm that easily...
내개 불가능이란 없다!
Nothing is impossible to me!
비를 달라.
Give us rain.
기우제 카라쿠리다.
It's Karakuri Rain Prayer!
안 됐냐.
Not yet?
어찌해도 부서지질 않소.
It's not getting destroyed at all-dasu.
자, 노부나가 다음은 무사시 놈들이다.
Now, it's time to finish Musashi bastards, since Nobunaga is done.
가랑이 찢어지오!
My crotch is being ripped-dasu!
-어찌된 거냐!
-저희를 추락시킬 생각입니다.
-What's going on?!
-He's trying to drop us!
나, 하늘 못 나오!
I can't fly-dasu!
나도 그래!
Me too!
다들 괜찮소?
Are you all right-dasu?
괜찮습니다. 노부나가를 찾읍시다.
I'm good. Let's find Nobunaga.
이렇게까지 당한 바 용서할 수 없어!
Since he has really done this to us, we cannot forgive him!
그게 맞소!
You're right-dasu!
노, 노부나가가 쓰러져 있소.
N- Nobunaga is down-dasu.
뭣이?!
What?!
대체 누가 이런 짓을...
Who did this?
한조겠지요.
It must be Hanzo.
한조는 애초에 주군인 이에야스 님을 배신하고 다음엔 시라누이 일족의 히미코 여왕을 배신하고, 지금 또 노부나가를 배신한 것입니다.
Hanzo betrayed Lord Ieyasu first, betrayed the queen Himiko of Shiranui Clan, and now he betrayed Nobunaga again.
무슨 끔찍한 놈이오!
How cruel of him-dasu!
부, 부탁이다.
D- do me a favor.
아직 살아 있었소...
You're still alive-dasu?
이 메가톤성을 파괴해라.
Destroy this Megaton Castle.
메가톤 성이오?
Megaton Castle?
하, 한조 따위에게 쓰이느니 파괴되는 쪽이 낫다.
It's better to be destroyed than being used by Hanzo.
그래도 큰일이오. 거대한 쇠망치라 해도 1개월이나 2개월은...
But, it's a big job-dasu! Even with a huge hammer, it'll take a month or two-dasu!
메, 메가톤성의 비밀은...
T- the secret of Megaton Castle is...
알겠소.
Got it-dasu.
악의 최후라는 것은 가련한 것이군요.
The last of evil is pitiful.
그렇습니다.
That's right.
이런 메가톤성은 쳐부수고 한조의 야망은 깨트려 주겠소!
We'll destroy this Megaton Castle and break Hanzo's ambitions-dasu!
좋다!
Right!
비를 달라.
Give us rain.
할아버지, 이런 겐나이 씨를 믿은 내가 바보였어.
Grandpa, I was a fool, to actually believe in this Mr. Gennai.
센짱 바보, 바보!
Sen-chan, you're an idiot!
덕분에 할아버지도 쓸데없이 시간을 낭비하고...
Thanks to that, you wasted your time, grandpa.
어라? 바람이 불어 와.
Huh? There's a wind.
(놀랐네, 참: 일본의 코미디언 미나미 신스케의 개그 펀치라인)
(bikkuri shitana, mou: I'm suprrised; Japanese comedian Minami Shinsuke's gag punchline)
어라, 설마 정말로? 내가 한 것이지만 놀랐네, 참!
Huh, really? Even for me, I'm surprised!
겐나이가 부른 폭풍은 왔다! 참으로 말 그대로, 질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
The storm called by Gennai came! Literally, wait for the stormy meal!
카라쿠리 검호전 무사시 로드
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
by Subdivers
어서 달아나라! 서두르지 마라!
Hurry up and escape, but do not rush!
어라, 농담삼아 했는데 정말로 와 주다니, 난 천재인가 봐.
Hey, I made that for a joke, but since it really worked, I must be a genius!
오, 이거야말로 단비구나!
This truly is a blessed rain!
케로키치! 이걸로 됐어!
Kerokichi! Our job is done!
잘 됐다. 이걸로 에도토피아가 구해졌어!
Great. Edotopia is now saved by this!
그래, 하나 생각났어!
I got a new poem!
비오는 날은
우산 쓰지 않으면
흠뻑 젖는다
On a day it rains
without a good umbrella
I get dripping wet
겐나이 씨, 이거 좀 심한 거 아냐? 이제 비는 필요 없어.
Mr. Gennai, isn't this too much? We already had enough rain.
그럼 기계를 멈춰 볼까.
Then, let me try stopping the machine.
안 되는 것 같네.
It doesn't work, after all!
비 피하자!
Let's go somewhere dry!
폭풍우가 칩니다, 한조 님.
The weather is stormy, Lord Hanzo.
그래, 말려들지 않도록 구름 위로 올라라!
I see. Go above the clouds, so that we don't get mixed up!
예! 동력실, 출력 전개!
Roger! Power room, increase power!
여기가 메가톤성의 동력실인가.
So, this must be the power room of Megaton Castle.
쳐들어가오.
Let's get in-dasu.
여기가 동력실? 대체 메가톤성의 동력원은 무엇입니까.
This is the power room? What is the power source of Megaton Castle?
저 다섯 명이 동력원이오.
Those five people are power sources-dasu.
어?
What?
노부나가의 이야기에 따르면 이 오괴승의 염력으로 메가톤성이 움직이고 있는 것 같소.
Nobunaga said that Megaton Castle is powered by the psychokinesis of these Five Mystery Monks-dasu.
음, 염력입니까.
Psychokinesis, eh?
그러나 이 오괴승이 앉아 있는 위치를 옆으로 비켜 놓으면, 염력은 역으로 메가톤성을 너덜너덜하게 할 것이오.
But by shifting the seats of these monks, their psychokinesis will work against Megaton Castle, leaving it in pieces.
염력에 빠져서 정신을 못 차리오.
They're too deep in psychokinesis to notice us-dasu.
좋아! 그건 마침 잘 됐군.
Great! That's just great.
아, 힘드오.
I'm tired-dasu.
이쪽에서도 끝났습니다.
I'm done, too.
어서 달아나자!
Let's hurry our way out!
무, 무슨 일이냐!
W- what's going on?!
모, 모르겠습니다!
I- I don't know!
어떻게 된 건지 알아봐라!
Find out what's going on!
계기판에서 이상하게 작동하고 있습니다!
The panel isn't working right!
젠장! 한 발짝만 더 가면 될 것을!
Damn! We were almost there!
전원 메가톤성을 버리고 달아나라!
Everyone, abandon Megaton Castle and get out!
메가톤성 따위 없어도 내겐 삼종의 신기가 있다!
Even without Megaton Castle, I have the Three Sacred Treasures!
제군! 날 따라와라!
Everyone! Follow me!
봉왕검!
Phoenix Sword!
됐나?
Did I do it?
제기랄!
Curse you!
네놈들, 아직도 끈덕지게 살아 있었느냐!
Were you bastards still alive?!
이 세상의 악을 쓰러트릴 때까지 죽지 않소!
We don't die until we're done with all the evil on this world-dasu!
메가톤성은 이제 끝이다! 포기해라, 한조!
Megaton Castle is no more! Give it up, Hanzo!
최후의 결판을 내 주겠다.
We will finish this right now!
바라던 바다!
Just as I wanted!
카라쿠리 변화!
Karakuri Shift!
겐토쿠 아머!
Gentoku Armor!
카라쿠리 변화!
Karakuri Shift!
칸우 아머!
Kanu Armor!
카라쿠리 변화!
Karakuri Shift!
초히 아머!
Chohi Armor!
메가톤성이 떨어지고 있어! 봐!
Megaton Castle is falling! Look!
어? 저기에는 무사시 씨가!
What?! Mr. Musashi's on there!
드디어 마지막 싸움이군요.
At last, that's the last battle.
여기서 바라볼 수밖에 없다니 유감이구려!
How deplorable, that we have to just gave at that!
다들 힘내서 한조를 끝장내 줘!
Everyone, do your best to finish Hanzo!
그래, 한 구절 생각났다.
Right, I got a new poem.
국왕 전하! 지금은 하이쿠를 읽고 있을 때가 아닙니다!
Your Highness! This is not a good time to read some Haiku!
네.
Understood.
무사시. 코지로. 쥬베. 힘내.
Musashi. Kojiro. Jube. Make it.
한조 놈. 어디까지 내게 대들어야 만족스러운 거냐, 거 참.
That Hanzo bastard. How much more do he have to defy me for him to be satisfied?
무사시 씨, 힘내쇼!
Mr. Musashi, do your best!
에, 저 메가톤성은 대단한 발명이야. 나도 저런 거 만들고 싶다.
That Megaton Castle is a great invention. I want to make something like that, too.
무사시 씨, 죽으면 안 돼. 만약 죽으면 나도 따라갈 거야.
Mr. Musashi, do not die. If you die, then I'll follow you.
그래도, 괜찮겠지. 무사시 씨, 강하니까. 게다가 나를 부인으로 해 주겠다고 했고!
But, I guess it'd be fine. Mr. Musashi is strong! Moreover, he said he'll marry me, after all!
무사시 씨! 힘내!
Mr. Musashi! Do your best!
꽤나 하는구나, 무사시!
Aren't you good, Musashi!?
당연하오! 나는 지팡구 제일의 무예가를 꿈꾸니까이오!
That's obvious-dasu! That's because I'm going to be the number one martial artist of Jipang-dasu!
이천일류 섬광검!
Nitenichiryu: Flash Sword!
네 칼날을 부러트려 주겠다!
I'll break your sword!
잘 됐소. 천공환은 오츠루 다음으로 소중한 것이니까이오.
What a relief-dasu. Tenkuumaru is important to me, next to Otsuru-dasu.
무사시! 각오해라!
Musashi! Prepare yourself!
무사시 님!
Mr. Musashi!
쥬베 씨, 살았소!
Mr. Jube, you saved me-dasu!
쳇, 쓸데없는 짓을!
Tch, how dare he do that!?
한조!
Hanzo!
네 부하는 전부 쓰러트렸다. 이제 남은 건 너뿐이다!
All your subordinates are now down! You're the only one remaining!
천하를 채갈 야망은 포기해라!
Give up your ambition to take over the world!
흥, 포기하라고? 나는 이미 천하를 가진 것과 마찬가지다!
Hmph, you're asking me to give it up? I already have the whole world in my hands!
국왕의 증표인 삼종의 신기는 내가 가지고 있으니 말이지.
That's because, I have the certificate of the king: the Three Sacred Treasures!
뭣이?! 왜 네가 삼종의 신기를!
What?! Why do you have the Three Sacred Treasures?!
국왕에게서 넘겨받았다.
The king gave this to me.
한조! 아무리 네가 삼종의 신기를 가지고 있다고 해도 아무도 널 국왕으로 인정하지 않을 테다!
Hanzo! Even if you have the Three Sacred Treasures, nobody will recognize you as a king!
인정하지 않으면 죽일 뿐!
Whoever does not recognize will be killed!
저대로는 안 되겠어! 추락하고 말 거야!
We can't stand watching that here! It'll fall!
어서 탈출해야!
They have to escape!
무사시 씨! 무사시 씨!
Mr. Musashi! Mr. Musashi!
내가 불리한 모양이구나. 흥, 다음에 다시 보자!
It seems that I'm at disadvantage. See you later again!
한조! 멈추시오!
Hanzo! Wait-dasu!
도망치지 마시오!
Don't run away!
이천일류 섬광검!
Nitenichiryu: Flash Sword!
젠장! 놓으시오! 젠장!
Damn! Unhand me-dasu! Damn you!
후후, 파리처럼 끈질긴 무사시여, 이대로 팔을 잡아 찢어 주겠다.
You have been a fly to me, Musashi. I'll tear off your arms for that!
아야야야야, 멈추시오!
Ow, ow, ow, ow! stop that-dasu!
아프오아프오아프오아프오!
It hurts! It hurts! That hurts-dasu!
젠장!
Damn!
어디서 감히, 무사시!
How dare you do that, Musashi?!
어? 삼종의 신기가!
The Three Sacred Treasures!
한조, 히미코 씨를 위한 복수이오!
Hanzo, this revenge is for Ms. Himiko-dasu!
이천일류 쌍룡검!
Nitenichiryu: Double Dragon Sword!
악은 망하오.
Evil will be perished-dasu.
뭔 소리냐! 난 아직 죽지 않았다!
What are you talking? I'm not dead yet!
무사시 씨!
Mr. Musashi!
한조는 쓰러졌다. 그 때, 무사시의 가슴 속에서 오가는 것은 무엇인가.
Hanzo is taken down. Right at that moment, what is recurring in Musashi's heart?
기나긴 싸움의 날들이 끝나고, 센히메, 코지로와의 여행도 끝을 알리고 있었다.
The long days of battles are over, and the trip with Senhime and Kojiro is also about to end.
오츠루!
Otsuru!
그러나 무사시의 여행은 지금 참으로 시작되려 하는 것일 지도 모른다.
But, Musashi's journey might be about to truly begin.
긴박한 다음 이야기를 기다려라!
Wait for the tense next story!
싸우고 맞았어
I fought and I got beaten
코피 쓩이야 랑데부
Nosebleed drips rendezvous
나도 지지 않으려 한발!
I can't lose, so take my blow!
핀치 펀치로 대역전
Pinch! Punch! I won by reversal
다음 시간 즐거운
Next is delightful lunchtime
급식일 텐데
But it's not delightful today
선생님의 벼락이
The thunder of my teacher
나한테만 떨어져 왔어
only hit me and nobody else
사정을 말해도
I tried to explain
들어주지 않는 채
But he won't listen
어떻게 해도 역시
Now whatever I do
눈물이 나오고 말아
I end up crying
울면서 밥먹으면
Don't cry when you eat, or
완전 맛없어
it tastes totally bad
울면서 밥먹으면
Don't cry when you eat, or
완전 맛없어
it tastes totally bad
울면서 밥먹으면
Don't cry when you eat, or
완전 맛없어
it tastes totally bad
울면서 밥먹으면
Don't cry when you eat, or
왠지 안타까워
you'll feel downhearted
무슨, 센짱하고 국왕 전하가 결혼하게 되었소.
Sen-chan and the Highness are going to marry-dasu!
그걸로 센짱의 제멋대로 구는 습관도 고쳐지고 여자다워 질 지도 모르오.
That might help with Sen-chan's selfishness, and she might become like other women-dasu!
그리고 나와 코지로는 간류 섬에서 결혼하오.
And Kojiro and I marry on Ganryu Island-dasu.
아니아니, 결투하게 되었소.
No, no, we have a match there-dasu!
누가 정말로 강한 무예가인지, 목숨을 건 사내간의 진검승부이오!
This is a serious match between men, risking our lives, which will determine the truly stronger martial artist!
다음 이야기! 무사시 대 코지로이오
Next story! Musashi vs. Kojiro
질풍노도의 마지막 이야기이오!
It's the stormy last story-dasu!
다음 이야기
무사시 대
코지로이오
재미있게 보세요!
Next Story
Musashi vs.
Kojiro
We hope you enjoy!